{
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "What is the syntax for binding to an input in a template",
      "answer": "[] - square braces",
      "example": "<app-my-component [myInput]=\"my input value\">",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the syntax for binding to an output in a template",
      "answer": "() - round braces",
      "example": "<app-my-component (myOutput)=\"outputHandler()\">",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "In CSS, what does @import do?",
      "answer": "It is a way to pull the contents of another css file into your css file. Note that you cannot load an @Import until the file declaring the import has been loaded.",
      "categories": [
        "css"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "List some different ways of adding css to your project",
      "answer": "1. add to angular.json - this adds your css to your javascript\n2. add a standard css link in the head of your document (eg <link rel=\"stylesheet\" type=\"text/css\" href=\"theme.css\">)\n3. use @import within another stylesheet\n4. create a local css file for your component and point your component to it\n5. add to the default styles.css (this is automatically created by the cli)",
      "categories": [
        "angular, css"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the different ways to encapsulate your component. Which is the default?",
      "answer": "None, Emulated, Native, ShadowDom. The default is Emulated",
      "categories": [
        "angular, css"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is Angular Material?",
      "answer": "This is a set of front-end components for Angular, designed as an implementation of Google's Material Design Specification",
      "categories": [
        "angular, css"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "In Shadow DOM terminology, what is the Shadow host",
      "answer": "The regular DOM node that the shadow DOM is attached to",
      "categories": [
        "web components, html"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "In Shadow DOM terminology, what is the Shadow tree",
      "answer": "The DOM tree inside the shadow DOM",
      "categories": [
        "web components, html"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "In Shadow DOM terminology, what is the Shadow boundary",
      "answer": "The place where the shadow DOM ends, and the regular DOM begins",
      "categories": [
        "web components, html"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "In Shadow DOM terminology, what is the Shadow root",
      "answer": "The root node of the shadow tree",
      "categories": [
        "web components, html"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "When Angular uses Emulated view encapsulation, how does it emulate the shadow DOM?",
      "answer": "Emulates native scoping of styles by adding an attribute containing surrogate id to the Host Element and pre-processing the style rules provided via styles or styleUrls, and adding the new Host Element attribute to all selectors",
      "categories": [
        "angular, html"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the difference between and attribute directive and a structural directive?",
      "answer": "",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Within a component annotation, what do square brackets around a directive selector denote",
      "answer": "",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Can you put more than 1 directive on the same element?",
      "answer": "",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the syntax for conditionally adding a class to an element using [ngClass]?",
      "answer": "",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "How would you get a reference to the element in an attribute directive",
      "answer": "You should inject ElementRef inside the constructor. To access the HTMLDivElement, use this.elementRef.nativeElement",
      "example": "export class MyAttributeDirective {\n    @Input('directiveBinding') varFromComponent;\n\n    constructor(private elementRef: ElementRef) {}\n}",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Can you apply an attribute directive to an angular component?",
      "answer": "",
      "example": "",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Does *ngIf remove from the DOM or just hide with display: none?",
      "answer": "",
      "example": "",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Under what circumstances would is be bad practice to manipulate DOM elements using ElementRef? How do you make changes to these elements?",
      "answer": "If using service workers you don't have access to the DOM. Make changes on a Renderer2 reference instead which decouples the thing you are making changes to from ElementRef",
      "example": "",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "In a directive, what does the hostlistener annotation do?",
      "answer": "",
      "example": "",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "In a directive, what does the hostbinding annotation do?",
      "answer": "",
      "example": "",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "If you're running an Angular application in dev mode, open dev tools, select the app route then type ng.probe($0) in the dev tools console. What would you expect to see?",
      "answer": "This will show a json representation of the root component",
      "example": "AppComponent {title: \"angular-quiz\", index: 4}\nindex: 4\ntitle: \"angular-quiz\"\nanswer: (...)\nquestion: (...)",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "How do you set an alias for an input binding?",
      "answer": "",
      "example": "",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "How do you pass an input property to an attribute directive?",
      "answer": "",
      "example": "",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "What does the * at the start of a directive mean?",
      "answer": "This denotes a structural directive. ",
      "example": "",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "What are the 3 types of angular directive",
      "answer": "1. component - a directive with a template. 2. structural directive - change the DOM by adding and removing DOM elements. 3. attribute directive - change the appearance or behaviour of an element or directive",
      "example": "",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "What is the Angular Testbed?",
      "answer": "This is a way of creating a type of Angular module specifically for testing. This enables the dependency injection to work, and provides a DOM to render your component into",
      "example": "beforeEach(async(() => {\n    TestBed.configureTestingModule({\n      declarations: [ HomePage ],\n    }).compileComponents();\n  }));\n\n  beforeEach(() => {\n    fixture = TestBed.createComponent(HomePage);\n    component = fixture.componentInstance;\n    fixture.detectChanges();\n  });",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "If Services have to be declared in the providers array (to enable hierarchical injection) how can they be lazy loaded?",
      "answer": "Using the @Injectable annotation (Angular 6+)",
      "example": "@Injectable({providedIn: 'root'})\nexport class MyService...",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]

    }, {
      "question": "If you find a Service with the @Injectable() annotation and update it with the following parameter: {providedIn: 'root'} what does that do?",
      "answer": "It is an alternative to adding the service to the providers in the root module. Detractors point out that it harms the cohesion of your software as providers can be scattered throughout the app. However, if only used in a lazy-loaded module it will be tree shaken out of the main module. Also if it isn't used at all this format allows the service to be tree shaken out of the build",
      "example": "",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "In Jasmine, What is the main difference between createSpy and spyOn?",
      "answer": "createSpy creates the method, spyOn turns an existing method into a spy",
      "categories": [
        "testing"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "Which Angular object has the forRoot method?",
      "answer": "RouterModule",
      "categories": [
        "angular, routing"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "If you have correctly set up your routing and try to navigate using <a href='/myValidPath' what would happen",
      "answer": "It will hit the server and reload the whole app",
      "categories": [
        "angular, routing"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "You're currently on the path /yada and you click a link containing the routerLink=\"yada\". Where does this attempt to link to",
      "answer": "/yada/yada - its a relative path",
      "categories": [
        "angular, routing"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "You're currently on the path /yada and you click a link containing the routerLink=\"./yada\". Where does this attempt to link to",
      "answer": "/yada/yada - its a relative path",
      "categories": [
        "angular, routing"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "You're currently on the path /yada and you click a link containing the routerLink=\"../yada\". Where does this attempt to link to",
      "answer": "/yada - this is a relative path which tells us to go back from /yada to / then appends yada",
      "categories": [
        "angular, routing"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "You're currently on the path /yada and you click a link containing the routerLink=\"/yada\". Where does this attempt to link to",
      "answer": "/yada - this is an absolute path",
      "categories": [
        "angular, routing"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "What does routerLinkActive do?",
      "answer": "It takes a string specifying the name of a class (or classes) to be added when that routerLink is active",
      "categories": [
        "angular, routing"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "You're currently on the route <your host>/blah. What route would the following code attempt to go to when clicked: <a [routerLink]=\"['/yada', 'blah', 99]\"...",
      "answer": "<your host>/yada/blah/99",
      "categories": [
        "angular, routing"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "What does [routerLinkActiveOptions]=\"{exact:\ntrue}\" do?",
      "answer": "Tells the routerLinkActive directive to only apply the specified class or classes if the routerLink is an exact match",
      "categories": [
        "angular, routing"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "You're importing an instance of ActivatedRoute into your component. Whats the difference between activatedRoute.snapshot and activatedRoute.params",
      "answer": "snapshot returns the current route data, params is an observable that updates when the route updates",
      "categories": [
        "angular, routing"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "If you add [queryParams]=\"{something: 1}\" to an anchor tag which already contains a routerLink path to \"/yada\" what would the url be?",
      "answer": "<your host>/yada?something=1",
      "categories": [
        "angular, routing"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "If you add [fragment]=\"something\" to an anchor tag which already contains a routerLink path to \"/yada\" what would the url be?",
      "answer": "<your host>/yada#something",
      "categories": [
        "angular, routing"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "Is EventEmitter an extension of an RxJS subject?",
      "answer": "Yes",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "Angular Elements compiles Angular components into something else - what is it?",
      "answer": "Web components",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "What is the difference between [routerLink] and routerLink",
      "answer": "When you use brackets, it means you're passing a bindable property of your component. Without brackets takes it outside the realm of angular so you're passing a primitive",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "[ngSwitch] can have 2 possible children - what are they?",
      "answer": "*ngSwitchCase and *ngSwitchDefault",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "What are the built in pipes?",
      "answer": "async, number, i18nSelect, i18nPlural, currency, date, json, slice, lowercase, uppercase, titlecase, async, percent, keyvalue",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "Can the safe-navigation be used with a pipe eg would the following work: (myObj | async)?.length?",
      "answer": "",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "Angular 8 introduced 'differential loading' - what is this?",
      "answer": "",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "What does srcset do",
      "answer": "",
      "categories": [
        "html"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "An Angular module includes a declarations array. The allowable classes are what described as declarable classes. Which types of classes are declarable?",
      "answer": "components, directives and pipes",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "Can an Angular module export declarable classes (Components, Directives and Pipes) from a module it has imported",
      "answer": "Yes",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "Where would you find entryComponents and what are they?",
      "answer": "To contrast the two types of components, there are components which are included in the template, which are declarative. Additionally, there are components which you load imperatively; that is, entry components",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "NgModule allows us to specify which declarable classes (Components, Directives and Pipes) are allowed for that module. Does Component allow the same?",
      "answer": "No",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "What is the difference between a pure Pipe and an Impure Pipe?",
      "answer": "",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "What does useHash do here? RouterModule.forRoot(appRoutes, {useHash: true})",
      "answer": "It uses the HashLocationStrategy instead of the default PathLocationStrategy. This means that a url that by default might look like: localhost:4200/blah instead shows as localhost:4200/#/blah",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "Name 3 lifecycle hooks",
      "answer": "Pick 3 of: ngOnChanges, ngOnInit, ngDoCheck, ngAfterContentInit, ngAfterContentChecked, ngAfterViewInit, ngAfterViewChecked, ngOnDestroy",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "Can directives implements lifecycle hooks (ngOnInit, ngOnChanges etc)?",
      "answer": "Yes",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "List 3 angular decorators",
      "answer": "Pick 3 of: @NgModule",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "What is: @Component",
      "answer": "",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "What is: @Injectable",
      "answer": "",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "What is: @Directive",
      "answer": "",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "What is: @Pipe",
      "answer": "",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "What is: @Input",
      "answer": "",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "What is: @Output",
      "answer": "",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "What is: @HostBinding",
      "answer": "",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "What is: @HostListener",
      "answer": "",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "What is: @ContentChild",
      "answer": "",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "What is: @ContentChildren",
      "answer": "",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "What is: @ViewChild",
      "answer": "",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "What is: @ViewChildren",
      "answer": "",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "Whats the difference between viewProviders and providers",
      "answer": "The viewProviders property allows us to make providers available to the component's view only, whereas the providers property makes a provider available to its content children and view children.",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "What does this CLI command do: ng g s heroes/hero",
      "answer": "ng (use cli) g (generate) s (service) heroes/ (create heroes folder) hero (create hero.service.ts service with the @Injectable({\n  providedIn: 'root'\n}) decorator)",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "If you use the @Injectable decorator with the ‘providedIn’ option, do you need to add it to the providers array of the module?",
      "answer": "No",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "What does ng-content do?",
      "answer": "It allows you to pass specify where in your template to output html added as a child of your component",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "What is string interpolation",
      "answer": "This is often referred to as moustache syntax. It allows us to reference component properties in our template",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "What is Ahead Of Time (AOT) compilation",
      "answer": "Angular is essentially a compiler. Much of the work involves taking a template and its css and turning it into JavaScript which can then be run on the client. AOT does this when you generate your prod build, JIT downloads the code, templates and css then does this on the client machine",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "What is ng-container",
      "answer": "this is a grouping element which doesn't actually get added to the DOM. Its not a directive or component - just a special case which angular looks for in the template",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "By convention what can do we use for directives",
      "answer": "Camel case",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }, {
      "question": "If you create a #reference property on a component with a play method. Does the following code work in a sibling component (click)='#reference.play()'",
      "answer": "Yes",
      "categories": [
        "angular"
      ]
    }


  ]
}
